Two Generations. Two Wars. One Story
Memorial Day is a action, drama, war film directed by Sam Fischer.
Memorial Day, 1993.
When 13-year-old Kyle Vogel discovers the World War II footlocker belonging
to his grandfather, Bud, everyone tells Kyle to put it back.
Luckily, he ignores them.
Although Bud has never talked about the war, he finds himself striking a deal with his grandson:
Kyle can pick any three souvenirs, and Bud will tell him the stories behind each one.
Memorial Day not only takes us on a journey into Bud's complicated
wartime past, but also into Kyle's wartime future.
As the two men share parallel experiences in combat, they come to realize
how that magical day on the porch shaped both of their lives.
SSGT. Kyle Vogel, played by Jonathan Bennett.
Bud Vogel, played by James Cromwell.
Young Kyle Vogel, played by Jackson Bond.
Lt. Kelly Tripp, played by Emily Fradenburgh.
Brandt, played by Steven Luke.
Memorial Day is a 2012 war film starring James Cromwell, Jonathan Bennett and
John Cromwell, directed by Sam Fischer and written by Marc Conklin.
The film explores themes of war victim, military weapons,
warbird, insurgent, army national guard.
The tone is emotional.